pressidium.com 2019-01-07

# Privacy Policy - Pressidium® Managed WordPress Hosting

#### Last Updated: May 16, 2018

**Pressidium®**  is a registered trademark owned and operated by **TechIO Limited** (“ _ **Pressidium**_ ”, “ _ **we**_ ”, “ _ **us**_ ”, and “ _ **our**_ ”). This Privacy Policy (“ ** _Policy_** ”) explains our privacy practices regarding personal information (as defined below) that we collect, store, share and use.

## Regarding the General Data Protection Regulation

The GDPR replaces current data privacy law, [giving more rights to you as an individual](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/) and more obligations to organizations holding your personal data. TechIO Limited is committed to being transparent about how it collects and uses your personal data, and to meeting its data protection obligations.

This Policy is published so you can be made aware of the increased rights you have in relation to the information we hold on you and the legal basis on which we are using it.

## Your rights

As a data subject under the GDPR, you have a number of rights. Subject to any exemptions provided by law, you can:

  * access and obtain a copy of your data on request;
  * require the organization to change incorrect or incomplete data;
  * require the organization to delete or stop processing your data, for example where the data is no longer necessary for the purposes of processing; and
  * object to the processing of your data where we are not required by overriding law/regulation as legitimate legal grounds for processing.

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us at [compliance@pressidium.com](mailto:compliance@pressidium.com)

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors using our services choose to interact with us in ways that require us to gather personally-identifying information.

The amount and type of information that we gather depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for our newsletter to provide their name and email address. Those who engage in financial transactions with us are asked to provide additional information, including the necessary personal and financial information required to process those transactions.

In each case, we collect such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with us. We do not disclose or process personally-identifying information other than as described below. Visitors can always refuse to supply us with their personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website- related activities.

This Policy tells you what to expect when we collect personal information. It applies to information we collect about:

  * Visitors to our website
  * People who contact us through the site’s contact forms
  * People who subscribe to our newsletter
  * People who contact us via social media
  * Job applicants
  * Our clients

It also contains further information on:

  * Cookies
  * Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information
  * Privacy Policy Changes

When someone visits pressidium.com we make use of the third party services of [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/), and [MixPanel](https://mixpanel.com/) to collect information and details of visitor behavior patterns in order to enhance visitor experience with more meaningful content.

The collected information which are passed from your browser to the aforementioned services are:

(a) your geo-location data, such as city, region, and country  
(b) technical information such as your browser, Operating System, screen resolution  
(c) visiting pages, duration

The above information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow the aforementioned services to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website. From time to time, we may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Along with the above services, we also make use of cookies for various reasons, ranging from core site functionality to marketing and analytics.

For more information on our use of cookies please see the respective section.

When someone contacts us via the contact forms found on our site, we collect their name and e-mail address along with an inquiry message. This information is collected in order to be able to communicate with the visitor in regards to their inquiry. This information is immediately forwarded and stored only in [Google Suite for Email](https://gsuite.google.com/).

## People who subscribe to our newsletter

We use a third party provider, [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/), to deliver our newsletter to our subscribers.

In order to make this possible, we collect the newsletter subscriber’s real name as well their e-mail address and we keep them stored for as long as the newsletter user remains subscribed. Every newsletter sent will also contain unsubscribe instructions by default.

We also gather statistics on email views and clicks using industry standard technologies, including tracking pixels to help us monitor and improve our newsletter. For more information on these tracking technologies, you can check the respective section.

We use a third party provider, [Hootsuite](https://hootsuite.com/) to manage our social media interactions.

If you send us a private or direct message via social media the message will be stored by Hootsuite. It will not be shared with any other organizations.

## Job applicants

As part of any recruitment process, we collect and process personal data relating to job applicants.

#### What information do we collect?

We collect a range of information about the applicant. This includes:

  * the applicant’s name, address and contact details, including email address and telephone number;
  * details of the applicant’s qualifications, skills, experience and employment history;

We collect information only provided directly or indirectly (i.e. recruitment agencies) by the actual applicant. For example, data might be collected in application forms, CVs or resumes, or collected through interviews or other forms of assessment. In addition, we may also collect personal data about the applicant from references supplied by former employers upon the applicant’s approval.

Applicant data will be stored internally by tools provided by [Atlassian](https://www.atlassian.com/), [Google Gsuite](https://gsuite.google.com/) and [Slack](https://slack.com/).

#### Why does TechIO Limited process applicant’s personal data?

Processing data from job applicants allows us to manage the recruitment process, assess and confirm a candidate’s suitability for employment and decide to whom to offer a job.

For future employment opportunities of which the applicant may be better suited (in case of an unsuccessful application), the applicant’s personal data may remain on file for a period of no more than 12 months after which it will be destroyed. We will ask the applicant’s consent before data is stored for this purpose, and the applicant may withdraw consent at any time.

#### Who has access to applicant’s data?

Applicant information will only be shared internally for the purposes of the recruitment process. This includes members of our HR and recruitment team, interviewers involved in the recruitment process, managers in the business area with a vacancy and IT staff if access to the data is necessary for the performance of their roles.

We will never share applicant data with third parties.

#### How does TechIO Limited protect applicant data?

We take the security of applicant data seriously. We have internal policies and controls in place to ensure that the applicant data is not lost, accidentally destroyed, misused or disclosed, and is not accessed except by our employees in the proper performance of their duties.

The applicant is under no statutory or contractual obligation to provide these data to us during the recruitment process. However, if the applicant chooses not to provide these information, we may not be able to process the application properly or at all.

## Our clients

Our services can only be accessed after the registration of a user account. In order to create a user account, a visitor is required to provide us with certain information, including their name, billing address, payment information (where applicable), email address, and phone number.

We use the above mentioned personal data in order to identify and fulfill any orders placed through our website (including processing payment information and providing our clients with invoices and/or order confirmations). Additionally, we use these data to:

  * Communicate with our clients;
  * Provide the client with information and news relating to our products or services.

We also use the above information along with the data we collect for visitors to our website to help us screen for potential risk and fraud.

Upon registration, client personal data are stored on our infrastructure and specifically on our internal secure Billing & Provisioning Systems. Payment information including credit card data are solely handled by our PCI-DSS 3 certified payment gateway, [BrainTree](https://www.braintreepayments.com/), which tokenizes and stores them in a highly encrypted, inaccessible, Data-Vault. Pressidium **®** , being fully PCI compliant, does not directly store, process, view or handle credit card numbers **at all** , and does not have the ability to retrieve or view card numbers from the aforementioned Encrypted Data Vault.

Client personal data required for accounting, invoicing and financial reporting purposes are stored on the accounting service, [Kashflow](https://www.kashflow.com/). Client data is also securely stored on [Amazon AWS S3](https://aws.amazon.com/s3/) for offsite backup and disaster recovery purposes according to our Business Continuity Plan.

Finally a small subset of client data is stored on [MixPanel](https://mixpanel.com/) for usage analytics and performance reporting of our provided services.

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Our services use cookies to help us identify and track visitors, their usage of our website, and their website access preferences. In some cases, we may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect Personal Information, or to collect information that becomes Personal Information if we combine it with other information.

#### What are cookies?

Cookies are small data files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies are widely used by online service providers in order to (for example) make their websites or services work, or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information.

Cookies set by the website owner or service provider (in this case, Pressidium) are called “first party cookies”. Cookies set by parties other than the website owner are called “third party cookies”. Third party cookies enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through the website or service you are using (such as advertising, interactive content and analytics). The third parties that set these third party cookies can recognize your computer both when it visits the website or service in question and also when it visits certain other websites or services.

#### Why do we use cookies and other tracking technologies?

We use first party and third party cookies for several reasons. Some cookies are required for technical reasons in order for our Websites and Services to operate, and we refer to these as “essential” or “strictly necessary” cookies. Other cookies enable us and the third parties we work with, to track and target the interests of visitors to our Websites, and we refer to these as “performance” or “functionality” cookies. For example, we use cookies to tailor content and information that we may send or display to you and otherwise personalize your experience while interacting with our Websites and to otherwise improve the functionality of the Services we provide. We also enable our users to employ cookies and similar tracking technologies in connection with their use of our Services in order to allow us and our users to track their subscribers. Finally, third parties serve cookies through our Websites and Services for advertising, analytics, and other purposes. This is described in more detail below.

#### Cookies served through our Websites

The specific types of first and third party cookies served through our Websites and the purposes they perform are described in further detail below

#### Strictly Necessary Cookies

These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms. You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will not then work. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information.

Cookies used

#### Performance Cookies

These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. If you do not allow these cookies we will not know if you have visited our site, and will not be able to monitor its performance.

Cookies used

#### Functional Cookies

These cookies enable the website to provide enhanced functionality and personalization. They may be set by us or by third party providers whose services we have added to our pages. If you do not allow these cookies then some or all of these services may not function properly.

#### Targeting Cookies

These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners. They may be used by those companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites. They do not directly store personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience less targeted advertising.

  * rxx (364 days)
  * __utma (729 days)
  * __utmc (Session)
  * _ga (729 days)
  * _gid (< 1 days)
  * __utmb (< 1 days)
  * __utmz (182 days)

  * datr (541 days)
  * fr (89 days)
  * lu (541 days)

  * SID (541 days)
  * HSID (541 days)
  * demographics (351 days)
  * VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE (55 days)
  * PREF (1871 days)
  * APISID (541 days)
  * SSID (541 days)
  * LOGIN_INFO (541 days)
  * YSC (Session)
  * SAPISID (541 days)

  * APISID (541 days)
  * SSID (541 days)
  * PREF (541 days)
  * SID (541 days)
  * SAPISID (541 days)
  * HSID (541 days)

  * UID (719 days)
  * UIDR (719 days)

#### Other tracking technologies

We and our third party partners may use other, similar technologies from time to time, such as web beacons, pixels (or “clear gifs”) and other tracking technologies. These are tiny graphics files that contain a unique identifier that enable us to recognize when someone has visited our Websites or, in the case of web beacons, opened an e-mail that we have sent them. This allows us, for example, to monitor the traffic patterns of users from one page within our Websites to another, to deliver or communicate with cookies, to understand whether you have come to our Websites from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website, to serve targeted advertisements to you and others like you, to improve site performance, and to measure the success of marketing campaigns. While you may not have the ability to specifically reject or disable these tracking technologies, in many instances, these technologies are reliant on cookies to function properly; accordingly, in those instances, declining cookies will impair the functioning of these technologies.

#### Targeted online advertising

We may engage one or more third party service providers to track and analyze both individualized usage and volume statistical information from interactions with our Websites. We also partner with one or more third parties (such as advertisers and ad networks) to manage and serve advertising on other sites.

These third parties use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags and similar tracking technologies to collect and use certain information about your online activities, either on our Websites and/or other sites or mobile apps, to infer your interests and deliver you targeted advertisements that are more tailored to you based on your browsing activities and inferred interests (“Interest Based Advertising”). For more information about this practice, click here: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.

See the Targeting Cookies section for a complete list of third-party provided cookies used on our website for these purposes.

#### How can I control cookies?

You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject any of the cookies we use to provide you with our various services.

**Website Cookie Preference Tool:** You can exercise preferences about what cookies are served on our Websites by visiting our cookie settings preference center.

**Browser Controls:** You can set or amend your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies. If you choose to reject cookies, you may still use our Websites though your access to some functionality and areas of our Websites may be restricted. As the means by which you can refuse cookies through your web browser controls vary from browser-to-browser, you should visit your browser’s help menu for more information.

**Disabling Most Interest Based Advertising:** Most advertising networks offer you a way to opt out of Interest Based Advertising. If you would like to find out more information, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

**Mobile Advertising:** You can opt out of having your mobile advertising identifiers used for certain types of Interest Based Advertising, including those performed by us, by accessing the settings in your Apple or Android mobile device and following the most recent published instructions. If you opt out, we will remove all data about you and no further data collection or tracking will occur. The random ID we (or our third party partners) had previously assigned to you will also be removed. This means that if at a later stage, you decide to opt-in, we will not be able to continue and track you using the same ID as before, and you will for all practical purposes be a new user to our system.

**Do Not Track:** Some Internet browsers – such as Internet Explorer, Firefox, and Safari – include the ability to transmit “Do Not Track” or “DNT” signals. Since uniform standards for “DNT” signals have not been adopted, our Websites do not currently process or respond to “DNT” signals. TechIO Limited takes privacy and meaningful choice seriously and will make efforts to continue to monitor developments around DNT browser technology and the implementation of a standard. To learn more about “DNT”, please visit [All About Do Not Track](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

#### How often will you update your cookie information?

We may update the above information from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to the cookies we use or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons. Please re-visit this Policy regularly to stay informed about our use of cookies and related technologies.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

TechIO Limited discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on TechIO Limited’s behalf or to provide services available at TechIO Limited’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others.

Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using TechIO Limited’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. TechIO Limited will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, TechIO Limited discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when TechIO Limited believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of TechIO Limited, third parties or the public at large.

If you are a registered Pressidium® user and have supplied your email address, we may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Pressidium® and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. TechIO Limited takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, we may change this Policy from time to time. We encourage visitors to frequently check this page for any changes. Information regarding the last update date will be appended both at the top and the bottom of this Policy. If you are an active client, you should also check your e-mail, as well as your dashboard for alerts to these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

#### Last Updated: May 16, 2018
